Finding aid for the One East 70th Street Papers, 1907-1931 HCFF.7
The Frick Collection/Frick Art Reference Library Archives
- Series VIII: Daily Life, 1914-1931, undated
  - Address book, circa 1914-1919 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    Contains names, mail and cable addresses, telephone numbers, out-of-town addresses for friends, relatives, political and business associates, physicians, art dealers, and others.
  - Books in the One East 70th Street Library, undated (Box 23, Folder 1)
    Entries list author, title, number of volumes, binding style, and bookcase number. A more complete inventory of books compiled shortly after Henry Clay Frick's death can be found in the Henry Clay Frick Papers, Series: Estate Files.
  - Dinner for French War Commissioners, 1917 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    Folder contains program of music for the evening and newspaper accounts of the event.
  - Dinners notebook, 1915-1919 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    Notebook containing details re: dinners and luncheons held mostly at One East 70th Street, with a handful of events at Eagle Rock. Details include the date, occasion, guest list, menu, and entertainment. An alphabetical list of invitees is located at the front of the volume.
  - Employment record book, 1914-1918 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    Cumulative record of employees at One East 70th Street, the New York garage (129 West 51st Street), Eagle Rock (Prides Crossing Mass.), Wenham Farm (Wenham, Mass.), Clayton (Pittsburgh, Pa.), and Henry Clay Frick's Pittsburgh office. Entries record names, titles, salaries, raises or other changes in compensation, and dates when individuals entered and left Henry Clay Frick's employ. Compiled by secretary Alice Braddel, beginning in 1914.
  - Employment record book - correspondence, 1914-1915 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    Contains correspondence, enclosures, and payroll sheets used by Alice Braddel in compiling and updating the employment record book.
  - Household diaries, 1914 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    Entries begin on 17 November 1914, the day on which the Fricks took their first dinner in the new house. Diaries record guests to the house, luncheons, dinners and other entertainments, purchase and installation of paintings and other works of art, and comings and goings of family members.
  - Household diaries, continued, 1915-1919 (Box 24, Folder 1-5)
  - Household diary excerpts, 1914-1919 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    Hand and typewritten excerpts from the One East 70th Street household diaries; compiled by Helen Clay Frick.
  - Household expense summaries, 1917-1919 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    Annual compilations of household expenses, including payroll, utilities, and groceries, and supplies.
  - Payroll and bills paid, 1915-1919 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    Volume chiefly records monthly payroll (October 1915-December 1918), bills approved and sent to Pittsburgh for payment (November 1915-January 1919), and bills paid by housekeeper Minerva C. Stone (November 1915-January 1919). Volume also contains daily work schedules for a handful of household positions, weekly cleaning schedule, list of magazines acquired for the house, holiday gifts to staff, and liquor and tobacco used to stock Frick's private railroad car.
  - Payroll and bills paid, 1916-1921 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    Volume records monthly payroll at One East 70th Street (October 1920-February 1921). Also documents bills for household expenses at Eagle Rock over the period of May 1916 to November 1919.
  - Payroll and bills paid, 1919 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    Volume records monthly payroll at One East 70th Street and Eagle Rock for 1919 (January-December). Also documents bills for household expenses over the same period.
  - Payroll receipt book, 1918-1920 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    Contains signatures of household employees denoting receipt of wages. Organized by household position (butler, chef, chambermaid, etc.)
  - Payroll receipt book, 1921-1931 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    Contains signatures of household employees acknowledging receipt of wages. Organized by the employee's name through August 1922; thereafter entries are made by month.
  - Service contracts, 1915-1918 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    Contains information regarding contracts with National District Telegraph Co., Holmes Electric Protective Co., and the New York Street Sprinkling and Flushing Co.
  - Service notebook, 1915-1920 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    Notebook recording employees who served in the Frick households at One East 70th Street and Eagle Rock. Entries are organized by year, and include the staff member's name, position, salary, and start date. Departure dates are also occasionally noted.
  - Telephone list, undated (Box 26, Folder 3)
    Telephone numbers of friends, hotels, and physicians. Mounted on leather stand; principally in Adelaide Frick's hand.
  - Wine cellar book, 1914-1918 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    Inventory of wines and other liquors at One East 70th Street. Entries record the name and vintage when applicable, along with when stock was received, and when bottles were used.